Guide to the Douglas Crimp Papers MSS.600
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series V. Writing, 1970-2016; 4.81 Linear Feet in 12 manuscript boxes; 19.71 Megabytes in 21 computer files
  This series focuses on Crimp's vast amount of writing on topics including queer theory, performance art, dance, photography, and film. His early advocacy of art that subverted the norm is evident in his articles on Agnes Martin (1973) and Joan Jonas (1976). His idea that museums are not neutral institutions is reflected in his book collaboration with Louise Lawler, On the Museum's Ruins. Crimp's advancment of queer theory can be seen in "Portraits of People with AIDS" (1992) and Before Pictures, which describes his own experiences growing up gay in Idaho in the 1950s. The materials in this series include published writing as articles, book chapters, and books, and unpublished writing, such as lectures, speeches, and notes.
  This series is arranged into two subseries: (VA.) Published and (VB.) Unpublished. The Published subseries is first arranged by articles and book chapters, followed by reviews, and ending with books. The Unpublished subseries is arranged chronologically
  - Subseries VA. Published, 1970-2016
    This subseries consists of drafts and manuscripts, notes, proofs, readers' notes, research material (articles and chapters from various publications), some correspondence, and in some cases, final publications of Crimp's writing. Also included are permissions for use and photographs and artwork used in the final publication. Various editions and reprints of select articles and books are included in multiple languages.
    - "Georgia Is a State of Mind," ARTnews, October 1970 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - "Quartered and Drawn," ARTnews, March 1971 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - "Agnes Martin: Numero, Misura, Rapporto," Data, vol. 3, #10, Winter 1973 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - "Opaque Surfaces," Arte Come Arte, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - "Joan Jonas's Performance Works," Studio International, vol. 192, #982, July-August 1976 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - "Daniel Buren's New York Work," Discordance/Cohérence by R. H. Fuchs and Daniel Buren, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Partial List of Published Essays, 1977-2012 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - "About Pictures," Flash Art, #88, 1979-2013 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - "Joan Jonas," Music Sound Language Theater: John Cage, Tom Marioni, Robert Barry, Joan Jonas, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - "Cindy Sherman: Making Pictures for the Camera," Young Americans, Allen Memorial Art Museum Bulletin, vol. 38, #2, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - "Richard Serra, le dépassement de la sculpture," Artistes, #7, January-February 1981 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - "The Museum's Old/The Library's New Subject," Parachute, Spring 1981 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - "Figure," Inespressionismo Americano by Germano Celant, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - "Drawings for Sale," ARQ, #8, July-August 1982 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - "Serra's Public Sculpture: Redefining Site Specificity," Richard Serra/Sculpture by Rosalind Krauss, 1984-1991; cuid38920 (Box 14, Folder 5-6, E-records Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_600_ER_6)
    - "The Art of Exhibition", 1984-1991; cuid38925 (E-records Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_600_ER_5)
    - "Sobre las ruinas del museo," La Posmodernidad edited by Hal Foster, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - "The Postmodern Museum," Parachute, 1987-1991; cuid38921 (Box 14, Folder 8, E-records Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_600_ER_7)
    - "Art in the '80s," Precis, 6, Spring 1987 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - "Positiv/Negativ: Eine Bemerkung zu Degas' Photographien," Wege zu Edgar Degas edited by Wilhelm Schmid, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - "Post-Moderni Museo," Taide, #2, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - "This Is Not a Museum of Art", 1989-1991; cuid38926 (E-records Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_600_ER_8)
    - "Ancien et nouveau: de l'objet de musée à la objet de bibliothèque," Les Cahiers du Musée National D'Art Moderne, Exposition de la Photographie, #35, Spring 1991 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - "Portraits of People with AIDS," Cultural Studies edited by Lawrence Grossberg, et. al, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - "De Vuelta al Museo sin Paredes," De Amor y Rabia: Acerca del Arte y el Sida by Juan Vicente Aliaga and José Miguel G. Cortés, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Contributions to Sex Panic!, November 1997 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - "Reconsidering Barcelona," The Photographic Paradigm: L & B edited by Annette W. Balkema and Henk Slager, vol. 12, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Contributions to Los Manifestos del Arte Posmoderno: Textos de exposiciones, 1980-1995 edited by Anna Maria Guasch, 1997-2000 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - "Estudos culturais, cultura visual," Revista USP, 1998-1999 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - "Getting the Warhol We Deserve: Cultural Studies and Queer Culture", 1998-2003 (Box 15, Folder 10, Box 16, Folder 1)
    - "Face Value: Andy Warhol's Blow Job", circa 1999-2005 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - "Lost: Cultural Studies, Visual Culture", circa 1999 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - "Mario Montez: For Shame", 2001-2003 (Box 16, Folder 4-5)
    - "Why Pictures Now and Again," Magazyn Sztuki and Obieg, vol. 28, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - "On the Museum's Ruins," October Files: Robert Rauschenberg, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - "AIDS: Cultural Analysis, Cultural Activism," AIDS Riot: Artist Collectives Against AIDS, New York, 1987-1994, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - "Del museo la biblioteca," Indiferencia y Singularidad, ed. by Glòria Picazo and Jorge Ribalta, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - "La actividad fotográfica de la posmodernidad," Efecto Real: Debates Posmodernos Sobre Fotografía, ed. by Jorge Ribalta, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - "Pictures," Reprint of 1977 Esssay, X-TRA, vol. 8, #1, Fall 2005 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - "Coming Together to Stay Apart," The Art of Queering in Art, ed. by Henry Rogers, 2007 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - "Success Is a Job in New York," Texte Zur Kunst, June 2008 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - "Synchronies of 'De-Synchronization'", circa 2009 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - "Prominence Given, Authority Taken: An Interview with Louise Lawler", circa 2013 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - "Reflections in a Golden Eye," Little Joe, #4, January 2013 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - "Dancing in the Art World," The Yale Dance Theater Journal, 2014 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - "What a Czech Gay Person Looked Like in 1984," Dik Magazine, #9, 2014 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - "Disss-Co" (A Fragment), Greater New York, MoMA PS1, 2015 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Reviews by Crimp, 1972-1979 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Recent Painting, Art Information Distribution, Slide Lecture 1, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - On the Museum's Ruins Photograph Permissions, 1986-1993 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - On the Museum's Ruins Photographs, 1986-1991 (Box 18, Folder 7-8, Box 19, Folder 1)
    - On the Museum's Ruins, Preface Proofs, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Museon Raunioilla (On the Museum's Ruins), Finnish Version, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Über die Ruinen des Museums (On the Museum's Ruins), German Version, 2003 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Sobre as Ruínas do Museu (On the Museum's Ruins), Portuguese Version, 2005 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - On the Museum's Ruins, Russian Version, 2015 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Melancholia and Moralism: Essays on AIDS and Queer Politics, Table of Contents and Considered Essays for Inclusion, circa 2001 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Melancholia and Moralism Permissions, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Melancholia and Moralism Photographs and Artwork, undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Melancholia and Moralism, Leather-Bound Edition, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Imágenes, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Posiciones Críticas: Ensayos sobre las políticas de arte y la identidad, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - "Our Kind of Movie": The Films of Andy Warhol, 2011; cuid38927 (E-records Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_600_ER_9)
    - "Letting Time Take Its Course," Vera Lutter, 2012 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Merce Cunningham, The Park Avenue Armory Event Liner Notes, 2012 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Before Pictures, 2014-2016; cuid38922 (Box 21, Folder 2, E-records Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_600_ER_10)
    - Pictures: S'Approprier la Photographie New York, 1979-2014, 2016 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Subseries VB. Unpublished, 1973-2015
    This subseries includes book proposals, lectures and speeches, and notes and notebooks. In some cases, materials also include correspondence, event programs, notes, drafts, and research materials.
    - "The Moroccan Cookbook," With Christian Belaygue, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Book Proposals and Article Drafts, circa 1975 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Notes and Research Material for Talk on Daniel Buren, Guggenheim Museum, 2005 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - "Back to the Turmoil," Talk for Colloquium on Agnes Martin, Dia: Beacon, circa 2005 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - "Photography," Paper delivered at College Art Association Annual Conference, 2007 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Notes for Paul Swan Presentation, Jack Smith Festival, Berlin, 2009 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Award Presentation Speech for Joan Jonas, Winner of Skowehegan Medal for Performance and Video, 2010 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Narrative Account of Career, circa 2010 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - "Outside In: A Study of the Interface between Mainstream and Self-Taught Art in the United States in the Twentieth Century," Talk for Clark Art Institute Symposium, 2014 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Lecture for Work/Travail/Arbeid: Anna Terese de Keersmaeker Exhibition, WIELS, 2014-2015 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Notes and Notebooks, undated (Box 22, Folder 11-13, Box 23, Folder 1-2)
- Series VI. Work by Others, 1947-2018; 1.75 Linear Feet in 5 manuscript boxes; 19.08 Gigabytes in 11 computer files
  This series consists of published and unpublished books, articles, and manuscripts; artwork; and photographs by others. Most of these materials were collected and consulted by Crimp as research for his writing and curatorial work on the artists of the "Pictures Generation," such as Sherrie Levine, Jack Goldstein, and Cindy Sherman; dance and performance artists, such as Yvonne Rainer; and AIDS activism and queer theory, as viewed in the writing of Michael Callen and Juan A. Suárez. Additionally, some material was sent to Crimp by friends, colleagues, and publishers for review or comment, as evident in inscribed works by Richard Meyer and Eve Kosofsky Sedwick. Some materials are in languages other than English. Many of the authors and artists listed here can also be found in Series VIII. Subject Files.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by author/artist/photographer or title.
  - "21 Films", 1978-1986; cuid38931 (E-records Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_600_ER_15)
  - "1000 Words," Various Artists. Artforum, 2006-2007 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Aletti, Vince. Disco Files, 1974-1978 (Box 23, Folder 4-5)
  - "Alexander's Legacy in the Classical World" Exhibition Photographs, undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Alloway, Lawrence. Introduction for Systemic Painting, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Ambrose, Kay. The Ballet-Lover's Pocket-Book, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Angell, Callie. Various Writing, 1994-2007 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Bagnato, Gene. Contact Sheet of Photographs of Crimp, circa 1980-1989 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Baldessari, John. Various Photographs of Artwork, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Bausch, Pina. Café Müller Photographs, circa 2007 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Borden, Lizzie and Susan Brockman. Artists' Performance, Art Information Distribution, Slide Lecture IV, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Boy Martyr Monthly, vol. 1, #1, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Brauntach, Troy. Photographs of Artwork, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Callen, Michael, ed. Surviving and Thriving with AIDS, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Castelli, Elizabeth A., et al. "History's Queer Touch: A Forum on Carolyn Dinshaw's Getting Medieval: Sexualities and Communities, Pre- and Postmodern", April 2001 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Chester, Alicia. "Love Letters to Anonymous People, or Photographs Never Taken, or This Is…Terry Gross", 2013 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Child, Abigail. Untitled Film, 1996; cuid38932 (E-records Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_600_ER_16)
  - De Miro, Ester. Cinema off e videoarte a New York, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Dean, Tacita. "Save Celluloid, for Art's Sake," guardian.co.uk, February 22, 2011 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Dyer, Geoff. "An Academic Author's Unintentional Masterpiece," The New York Times, July 22, 2011 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Esquivias, Patricia. Various Films, 2005-2008; cuid38929 (E-records Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_600_ER_13)
  - Eyes Looking for a Head to Inhabit, Exhibition Catalogue, Museum Sztuki, 2011 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Fassbinder, Rainer Werner. Stills from Year of the Thirteen Moons, Galerie Buchholz, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Ferre, Rosario. La Muñeca Menor (The Youngest Doll), circa 1976 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Fierce Pussy. For the Record and Transmission III, 2013-2018 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Film Stills (Unknown Film and Photographer), circa 1950-1959 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Fisher, Morgan. Interior Color Beauty Exhibition Catalogue, 2013 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Gaillard, Cyprien. The Smithsons, 2005; cuid38930 (E-records Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_600_ER_14)
  - General Idea Exhibition Catalogue, Camden Arts Centre, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Giard, Robert. Photographs of Crimp, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Golden Years: Materialien und Positionen zu Queerer Subkultur und Avantgarde Zwischen, 1959-1974 Review, circa 2006 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Goldstein, Jack. Photographs, Negatives, and Descriptions of Artwork, circa 1977 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - "Grids, Folds, Disco" (Unknown Author), circa 2016 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Harvey, Michael. Artists' Films, Art Information Distribution, Slide Lecture VII, 1975 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Koch, Kenneth. "The Artist," ARTnews, March 1958 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Kurnick, David. "Carnal Ironies," Raritan, vol. 29, #4, Spring 2010 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Lawler, Louise. Slides of Artwork, Matches from Exhibition, and Coloring Postcards, 1978-2017 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Leung, Simon. "Squatting through Violence," Documents, #6, Spring/Summer 1995 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Levine, Sherrie. Artwork and Writing, 1977-1980 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Lewitt, Sol. Photographs of Artwork, 1968-1976 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Litt, T. L. Photographs of Crimp, 1991 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Longo, Robert. Photographs of Artwork and Performances, 1976-1978 (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Los Angeles Contemporary Exhibitions (LACE) Catalogues, 1988-1990 (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Louise Lawler, Adrian Piper, and Cindy Sherman Exhibition Catalogue, Artists Space, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Magnus Magazin, December 1990 (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Maimon, Vered. "The Third Citizen: On Models of Criticality in Contemporary Art Practices," October, vol. 129, Summer 2009 (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Mangolte, Babette. Various Films, 1975-1999; cuid38928 (E-records Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_600_ER_12)
  - Martin, Agnes. Photographs of Artwork, 1963-1967 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Mass, Lawrence D. "Sexual Imperialism, Private Lives, Political Contexts: The Case of Tony Pipolo, PhD", 2000 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - McClelland, Maurice. "The Puppet Theatre of Robert Anton," The Drama Review: TDR, vol. 19 #1, March 1975 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Meyer, Richard. "The Jesse Helms Theory of Art," October, #104, Spring 2003 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - The Museum World: Arts Yearbook 9, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Nabokov, Vladimir. "Invitation to a Transformation" (Reprint), 1999 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - O'Hara, Frank. What's with Modern Art: Selected Short Reviews and Other Art Writings, 1999 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - O'Malley, Alice. Photograph of Crimp, 2016-2017 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Opie, Catherine. Photographs of Crimp, 2001 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Phillips, Adam. "On Being Bored," On Kissing, Tickling, and Being Bored, 1993 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - "Poems for Douglas", December 2018 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Rainer, Yvonne. Writing and Photographs of Performances, 1967-2009; cuid38923 (Box 25, Folder 12, E-records Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_600_ER_11)
  - Ratcliff, Carter. Illustration and Allegory Exhibition Catalogue, Brooke Alexander, Inc., 1980 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Regelson, Rosalyn. Various Writing, 1951-1969 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Ross, David. Artists' Video, Art Information Distribution, Slide Lecture VI, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Sedgwick, Eve Kosofsky. Various Writing, 1990-1991 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Serra, Richard. Plans and Notes for St. John's Rotary Arc, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Shapiro, Joel. Photographs of Artwork, 1972-1973 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Siegel, Marc. "The Gossip of Images" and "Decorating Power", 2000-2005 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Smith, Philip. Photographs and Negatives of Artwork and Writing, 1976-1977 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Sontag, Susan. "A Lexicon for Available Light" and "Happenings: An Art of Radical Juxtaposition", 2001-2012 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Specter, Michael. "Higher Risk," The New Yorker, May 23, 2005 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Stone, Katie. "Joan Jonas, Beyond the Frame," MA Dissertation, 2003 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Suárez, Juan A. "Queer Performance in Jack Smith and Andy Warhol: Of Gender, Fragments, and Unassimilable Remains", circa 1995 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Tavel, Ronald. Various Writing, 1966-1997 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Tschumi, Bernard. Architectural Manifestoes Catalogue and Advertisements for Architecture Postcards, 1976-1978 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Ueda, Takahrio. "Body (Un-Installed)", February 29, 2008 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Unknown Photographs, circa 1950-1969 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Unknown Photographer, Photographs of Crimp, circa 1980-1999 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Urbach, Henry. "Spatial Rubbing: The Zone," Sites 25, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Weathers, Chelsea. "Warhol Out West: Lonesome Cowboys Leave the City", circa 2000-2010 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Wodiczko, Krzysztof Award Presentation Speech for Skowhegan Medal (Unknown Presenter), 2008 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Wolfe, Tom. "The Girl of the Year," The Kandy-Kolored Tangerine-Flake Streamline Baby, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Wolff, Janet. "The Invisible Flâneuse: Women and the Literature of Modernity," Theory, Culture, and Society, Vol. 2, #3, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 16)
- Series VII. Printed Matter, 1977-2018; 1.31 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes
  Printed matter consists of magazine articles and peer-reviewed articles on or about Crimp. Many of the articles are interviews with Crimp, discussing his writing and curatorial work on the "Pictures Generation" artists, dance and performance art, photography and film, and queer theory. Most of the articles are related to recent publications, exhibitions, or lectures. The peer-reviewed articles often cite Crimp in support of, or sometimes as opposed to, the authors' writing on these topics.
  Arranged into two subseries: (VIIA.) General and (VIIB.) Reviews.
  - Subseries VIIA. General, 1980-2018
    The General subseries contains interviews with Crimp, articles about him, or articles/clippings that reference him. Also included are some publicity materials for his publications.
    Arranged chronologically.
    - List of Interviews, 1980-2003 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - General, 1990-1994 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - General, 1995-1997 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - General, 2000-2003 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - General, 2006-2010 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - General, 2011-2012 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - General, 2013-2015 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - General, 2016-2018 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Subseries VIIB. Reviews, 1977-2018
    Reviews include reviews of Crimp's writing (mostly books and exhibition catalogues) and exhibitions.
    Arranged chronologically by publication or exhibition.
    - Pictures Exhibition, 1977-1978 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Image Scavengers: Photography, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - AIDS Demo Graphics, 1990-1995 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - How Do I Look? Exhibition and Book, 1990-1993 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - AIDS: Cultural Analysis/Cultural Activism, circa 1993 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - On the Museum's Ruins, 1993-1997 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Melancholia and Moralism, 2002-2004 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Mixed Use, Manhattan Book, Edited with Lynne Cooke, 2011 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - "Our Kind of Movie": The Films of Andy Warhol, 2012-2013 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Pictures: S'Approprier la Photographie New York, 1979-2014, 2016-2018 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Before Pictures Exhibition and Book, 2016-2018 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Alvin Baltrop: "At the Hudson River Piers", Exhibition Curated by Crimp, 2017 (Box 28, Folder 10)
- Series VIII. Subject Files, 1944-2018; 2.19 Linear Feet in 5 manuscript boxes
  This series contains research material (clippings, photocopied articles and book chapters, and exhibition catalogues) on various individuals and topics of interest to Crimp, including dance theory, film, queer theory, and "Pictures Generation" artists (Jack Goldsteing, Sherrie Levine, and Robert Longo). He used many of these materials as research for his writing and curatorial work. Additional topics include other art exhibitons to which he was invited, as seen in the poster, brochures, and postcards in the Art Exhibitions folder, and writing about contemporary art, as viewed in issues of Parachute and Newspaper Jan Mot in the Art Magazines folder. Many of the individuals listed here also can be found in Series VI. Work by Others.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Art Exhibitions, 1981-2008 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Art Magazines, 1972-2015 (Box 28, Folder 12, Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Atlas, Charles, 1971-1997 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Ballet, 1945-2010 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Book Catalogues, German, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Brown, Trisha, 1966-2010 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Cage, John, 2012-2013 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Cornell, Joseph, 1980-2009 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Cunningham, Merce, 1970-2018 (Box 29, Folder 8-9)
  - Dance Theory, 1978-2004 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Division of Liberal Studies, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Film, 1955-2012 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - German Artists, 1985 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Goldstein, Jack, 1977-2010 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Human Rights, 1987-1994 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Jonas, Joan, 1972-1975 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Lawler, Louise, 1987-1994 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Leonard, Zoe, 2008-2012 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Levine, Sherrie, 1979-1981 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Lewitt, Sol, 2001 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Longo, Robert, 1977-1981 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Male Models, 2003 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Martin, Agnes, circa 1970-2008 (Box 30, Folder 14-15)
  - Montez, Mario, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Photography, 1979-2010 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Postcards, undated (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Queer Activism, 1991-1998 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Queer Studies, 1991 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Queer Theory, 1989-2012 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Rainer, Yvonne, 1965-2015 (Box 31, Folder 3-4)
  - Sherman, Cindy, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Sontag, Susan, 1966-2005 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Swan, Paul, 1944 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Tavel, Ronald, 1963-2009 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Warhol, Andy, 1966-2010 (Box 32, Folder 1-2)
  - Weiner, Lawrence, 1965-1974 (Box 32, Folder 3)